<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Georg J. A. Hähn</title>
    <link>https://georghaehn.netlify.app/author/georg-j.-a.-hahn/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://georghaehn.netlify.app/author/georg-j.-a.-hahn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Georg J. A. Hähn</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 12:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://georghaehn.netlify.app/author/georg-j.-a.-hahn/avatar_hubac488b0ee4028e529064ec692d55159_578148_270x270_fill_q75_lanczos_center.jpg</url>
      <title>Georg J. A. Hähn</title>
      <link>https://georghaehn.netlify.app/author/georg-j.-a.-hahn/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Year PhD Recap</title>
      <link>https://georghaehn.netlify.app/talk/first-year-phd-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://georghaehn.netlify.app/talk/first-year-phd-recap/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old-growth forest as microclimate refugia</title>
      <link>https://georghaehn.netlify.app/project/ogf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://georghaehn.netlify.app/project/ogf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The journey of my PhD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In time of profound biodiversity crisis, we still know little about biodiversity distribution, which might hinder conservation efforts. I want to understand the distribution of plant biodiversity and where it might be able to survive recent and future climate change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my PhD I investigate how structural complex forests are able to buffer climate change and their potential in being save havens for biodiversity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BES 2022 Annual Meeting</title>
      <link>https://georghaehn.netlify.app/talk/bes-2022-annual-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://georghaehn.netlify.app/talk/bes-2022-annual-meeting/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M.Sc. Defence 2022</title>
      <link>https://georghaehn.netlify.app/talk/m.sc.-defence-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://georghaehn.netlify.app/talk/m.sc.-defence-2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sPlot</title>
      <link>https://georghaehn.netlify.app/project/splot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://georghaehn.netlify.app/project/splot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Global Vegetation Database OR Where I learned to wrangle data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.idiv.de/en/splot.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;sPlot&lt;/a&gt; - The Global Vegetation Database: sPlot is the largest repository for plant community data in the world, containing almost 2 million records with full lists of plant species co-occurring in small areas (plots). The facility was first established as a working group funded by sDiv, then assumed as an iDiv research platform. By integrating national and continental vegetation databases, sPlot aims at understanding global patterns in plant diversity across facets, biomes and scales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supervised by Francesco M. Sabatini I prepared and included new vegetation data for the database since 2020. Due to the fantastic supervision I was soon very engaged to the idea of a master thesis investigating how functional and phylogenetic diversity distributes globally in vascular plant communities. To understand this relationship we created the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.idiv.de/fileadmin/content/Files_sPlot/Documents/FAMILY-TREE_sPlot3.0.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;phylogenetic backbone&lt;/a&gt; for sPlot and used the existing link to the trait database &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.try-db.org/TryWeb/Home.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;TRY&lt;/a&gt; to calculate functional and phylogenetic diversity for almost two million vegetation plots. Surprising results can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41559-024-02589-0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TreeDì</title>
      <link>https://georghaehn.netlify.app/project/treedi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://georghaehn.netlify.app/project/treedi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;International Research Training Group TreeDì (GRK 2324)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.idiv.de/en/treedi.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;TreeDì - 林地&lt;/a&gt; - Tree Diversity Interactions: The role of tree-tree interactions in local neighborhood in Chinese subtropical forests&amp;rdquo; is an International Research Training Group funded by the German Research Foundation (DFG) and the University of Chinese Academy of Sciences (UCAS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Biodiversity-Ecosystem-Functioning (BEF) research in forests has become a vibrant field of research in the last decade. The aim of TreeDì - 林地 (lín dì, forest land) is to understand how tree-tree interactions in local neighborhood of varying diversity translate into the observed positive tree species richness effects on key ecosystem functions at the community scale. Tree-tree interactions range from above- and belowground competition to resource use complementarity and facilitation. In-depth knowledge of each interaction type and interdisciplinary teamwork are essential to understand the underlying processes. All research projects are carried out on the BEF-China platform in subtropical China  - the largest forest BEF experiment worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the sub-project (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.idiv.de/en/web/treedi/research_projects.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;P8G&lt;/a&gt;), I was supervised by &lt;a href=&#34;https://remybeugnon.netlify.app/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Rémy Beugnon&lt;/a&gt; focusing on litter functional dissimilarity effects on litter decomposition based on a common garden approach (&lt;a href=&#34;files/bachelorarbeit_georg.haehn_18.08.2020.pdf&#34;&gt;B.Sc. thesis&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
